<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>object thinking on raffaeleflorio ~/</title>
    <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/tags/object-thinking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in object thinking on raffaeleflorio ~/</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/tags/object-thinking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Implementing an Event Loop in Java for Fun and Profit</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/implementing-an-event-loop-in-java-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/implementing-an-event-loop-in-java-for-fun-and-profit/</guid>
      <description>The event loop pattern always fascinated me. I found it interesting, useful, and compatible with object-oriented programming. A lot of us know it thanks to Node.js.
For some reason, recently, I have been looking to implement it and experiment with it. And I finally got the opportunity to do so at work.
Event Loop Concepts An event loop doesn&amp;rsquo;t do too much. We can ask it to start and stop itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objects &amp; Pursuit of Happiness: Understanding Object Oriented Programming (OOP)</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/object-and-pursuit-of-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/object-and-pursuit-of-happiness/</guid>
      <description>Responsibilities are what differentiate objects. They represent what an object can do for us. And in a good object-oriented system, each object should have correct responsibilities.
Is there any criterion to help us to verify and find them? I think happiness is a good answer.
A metaphor The common way to define objects is wrong. Objects are not just data plus functions. In other words, objects are not a C file containing structs and related functions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
