<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pwn on raffaeleflorio ~/</title>
    <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/tags/pwn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pwn on raffaeleflorio ~/</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/tags/pwn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AUCTF 2020 Writeup - Remote School</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/remote-school-auctf2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/remote-school-auctf2020/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the fourth and last pwn challenge. It was solved 63 times and it was worth 960 points.
Description:
 Dear Student,
Due to COVID-19 concerns our curriculum will be moving completely to online courses… I know we haven’t even started our school year yet so this may come as a shock. But I promise it won’t be too bad! You can login at challenges.auctf.com 30013.
Best, Dean of Eon Pillars</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUCTF 2020 Writeup - House of Madness</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/house-of-madness-auctf2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/house-of-madness-auctf2020/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the third pwn challenge. It was solved 100 times and it was worth 897 points.
Description:
 Welcome to the House of Madness. Can you pwn your way to the keys to get the relic?
nc challenges.auctf.com 30012
Note: ASLR is disabled for this challenge
 You could download the binary here.
$ sha256sum ./house_of_madness 15b1a68ae0e1d4eee4f917cc92412d90fd3a4adbb5a55a83b115e0f438baaf93 house_of_madness Exploitation When we launch the program shows a banner and it asks us to make a choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUCTF 2020 Writeup - Thanksgiving Dinner</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/thanksgiving-dinner-auctf2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/thanksgiving-dinner-auctf2020/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the second pwn challenge of AUCTF 2020. It was solved 238 times and it was worth 408 points.
Description:
 I just ate a huge dinner. I can barley eat anymore… so please don’t give me too much!
nc challenges.auctf.com 30011
Note: ASLR is disabled for this challenge
 You could download the binary here
$ sha256sum ./thanksgiving_dinner 2307af59beead6a2377c3beb2ff26f70d5732ec6b651b5c31e58b8f692bfb70c thanksgiving_dinner Exploitation The program simply ask for an input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shellcode Injection - Old but gold</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/mprotect-urop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/mprotect-urop/</guid>
      <description>Intro Some time ago, a friend of mine (dag-tech), asked me about a technique to run a shellcode with NX enabled. So he gave me a simple program:
//src.c #include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;#include &amp;lt;unistd.h&amp;gt; int main(int argc, char **argv) { char buf[16]; puts(&amp;#34;Can you pwn me????&amp;#34;); read(0, buf, 512); return 0; } $ gcc -z noexecstack -fno-stack-protector -o vuln src.c $ checksec vuln Arch: amd64-64-little RELRO: Partial RELRO Stack: No canary found NX: NX enabled PIE: No PIE (0x400000) The approach The issue with NX is that we cannot execute code in writable memory segment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackCon&#39;19 writeup - baby b0f</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/babyb0f-hackcon19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/babyb0f-hackcon19/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the first and easiest pwn challenge. It was solved 117 times and it’s worth 100 points.
Description:
 It’s a b0f , Can’t be easier than that.
 You could download the binary here.
$ sha256sum ./babyb0f 68344bb2c6aa56fdcc75379b3ced882abdf4e9bffa0bba63006dfb6c11ed7c47 babyb0f Exploitation The program simply asks for an input that overflow a buffer:
$ ./baby_b0f AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA Try Again Segmentation fault (core dumped) $ checksec ./baby_b0f Arch: amd64-64-little RELRO: Partial RELRO Stack: No canary found NX: NX enabled PIE: No PIE (0x400000) As usual I opened the binary with r2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackCon&#39;19 writeup - babypwn</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/babypwn-hackcon19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/babypwn-hackcon19/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the second pwn challenge. It was solved 36 times and it’s worth 451 points.
Description:
 You don’t need eip control for every pwn.
 You can download the binary here
$ sha256sum ./babypwn 57b32556465e890bdefdcccd6e515f6a2888300f48e9b7a7df0bb66694bda45b babypwn Exploitation The program asks five input, echoes them back and prints a message of failure. However there is a segfault caused by a buffer overflow.
$ ./babypwn 1 2 3 4 5 1 2 3 4 5 Naaa , Try HArder $ .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackCon&#39;19 writeup - Not So Easy B0f</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/notsoeasyb0f-hackcon19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/notsoeasyb0f-hackcon19/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the third pwn challenge. It was solved 29 times and it’s worth 469 points.
Description:
 I have stack canaries enabled, Can you still B0f me ?
 In addition to the binary there is also a specific libc.
You can download the binary here and the libc here
$ sha256sum notsoeasyb0f notsoeasyb0f-libc.so 9cdc861043359904c6807d31990f7369c1fec2d25e545e263bb4ae2e5786883e notsoeasyb0f 74ca69ada4429ae5fce87f7e3addb56f1b53964599e8526244fecd164b3c4b44 notsoeasyb0f-libc.so Exploitation This program asks for a name, echoes it back, then it asks a sentence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>