<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on raffaeleflorio ~/</title>
    <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on raffaeleflorio ~/</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Science Behind Full-Text Search Engines</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/the-science-behind-full-text-search-engines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/the-science-behind-full-text-search-engines/</guid>
      <description>Recently I started using Elasticsearch, which is one of the most known search engine. The things it allows to do fascinated me. That’s why I dove into informational retrieval (IR), the science behind it. It’s a huge topic, and a silver bullet for search engines doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist. It is user needs and expectations that tailors the model and the process to find information. This user-centric vision to measure the quality of an IR system captured me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Run Podman and Docker-Compose on Windows</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/how-to-run-podman-and-docker-compose-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/how-to-run-podman-and-docker-compose-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>As you know containers are a Linux thing. Microsoft introduced its solution but I’ve never seen them used.
To use containers we have mainly two alternatives: docker and podman. I prefer the latter for two reasons. Because it has a daemonless architecture and because it doesn’t need root permission. But using it with docker-compose on Windows is tough. That’s why I decided to write and share this story.
Motivation I think using Docker Desktop on Windows is the fastest way to use containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncover the Alias Pattern</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/uncover-the-alias-pattern/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/uncover-the-alias-pattern/</guid>
      <description>While I write OOP code I apply some practices of Elegant Objects.
One of them is that classes should be final. This means that they cannot be extended through inheritance but only through composition.
The advantage is simplicity. I mean that, in this way, each object is seen as a cohesive block. What interest to its clients is its exposed behaviour. Nothing more. Instead, through extension, a client can break it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Thinking, Boundaries and Reality</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/object-thinking-boundaries-and-reality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/object-thinking-boundaries-and-reality/</guid>
      <description>Ask a software developer, what is &amp;lsquo;good code?&amp;rsquo; They likely will answer something along the lines of, &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s clean or elegant code.&amp;rdquo;
It&amp;rsquo;s likely this person will further list SOLID principles and design patterns as a way to legitimize cleanliness or elegance.
I think the way this relationship dynamic is interpreted is wrong. What I mean is that SOLID and design patterns do not simply imply good code. It&amp;rsquo;s actually the other way around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing an Event Loop in Java for Fun and Profit</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/implementing-an-event-loop-in-java-for-fun-and-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/implementing-an-event-loop-in-java-for-fun-and-profit/</guid>
      <description>The event loop pattern always fascinated me. I found it interesting, useful, and compatible with object-oriented programming. A lot of us know it thanks to Node.js.
For some reason, recently, I have been looking to implement it and experiment with it. And I finally got the opportunity to do so at work.
Event Loop Concepts An event loop doesn&amp;rsquo;t do too much. We can ask it to start and stop itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objects &amp; Pursuit of Happiness: Understanding Object Oriented Programming (OOP)</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/object-and-pursuit-of-happiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/object-and-pursuit-of-happiness/</guid>
      <description>Responsibilities are what differentiate objects. They represent what an object can do for us. And in a good object-oriented system, each object should have correct responsibilities.
Is there any criterion to help us to verify and find them? I think happiness is a good answer.
A metaphor The common way to define objects is wrong. Objects are not just data plus functions. In other words, objects are not a C file containing structs and related functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java: The Object Equality Problem</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/java-the-object-equality-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/java-the-object-equality-problem/</guid>
      <description>I was writing some Java test code when I faced up the voracity of the equals method. It presents, despite its ostensible simplicity, a tricky problem.
I&amp;rsquo;d like to emphasize that this is not a specific Java issue. For example C# has a homologous way.
A bit of Java context The Object class is the root of every class. It defines various methods and equals is one of them. By default this method has a simple behavior: an object x is only equals to itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Framework: To Use Or Not To Use, That Is The Question</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/spring-to-use-or-not-to-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/spring-to-use-or-not-to-use/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to write OOP code with Spring. From its core it promotes the use of singletons and anemic data structures a.k.a. data &amp;ldquo;objects&amp;rdquo; a.k.a. DTO. This fuels procedural programming and kills OOP.
In the next paragraphs I&amp;rsquo;ll highlight three major Spring components involved. I start from the core.
IoC Container The core of Spring is the IoC container, represented by the ApplicationContext interface. Basically it defines a context through which we get beans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to Simplicity: Tests Are Not Tests [Part Two]</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/road-to-simplicity-tests-are-not-tests-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/road-to-simplicity-tests-are-not-tests-part-two/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the second post of Road to Simplicity. And it&amp;rsquo;s about the role of tests in software writing.
(The first part is about the goal of the series and hexagonal architecture)
Test and correctness I think that it&amp;rsquo;s inappropriate to associate test with verification of correctness. After all with a test we can verify that a software module (e.g. a function) returns an expected output with a given input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road to Simplicity: Hexagonal Architecture [Part One]</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/road-to-simplicity-hexagonal-architecture-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/road-to-simplicity-hexagonal-architecture-part-one/</guid>
      <description>Intro Software writing taught me that: a well written software is a simple software.
So I started to think how to achieve simplicity in a methodological way. This is the first post of a series about this methodology.
Naturally it&amp;rsquo;s a snapshot because it&amp;rsquo;s in constant evolution.
Simplicity A definition of simplicity is:
The quality or condition of being easy to understand or do.
Oxford dictionary (https://www.lexico.com/en/definition/simplicity)
So, a simple software is a software that is easy to understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosa significa contribuire alla cultura hacker?</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/cultura-hacker/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/cultura-hacker/</guid>
      <description>Hacker e dubbio Col tempo ho eguagliato la cultura hacker alla cultura del dubbio.
Dunque contribuire alla cultura hacker significherebbe contribure alla cultura del dubbio. E immagino che, solo questo, non significhi molto.
A tal proposito partirei dalla relazione fra hacker e dubbio.
Chi è un hacker? Una definizione di hacker che va dritta al punto è:
Un hacker non è altro che una persona che ama capire come funzionano le cose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What does it mean to contribute to the hacker culture?</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/hacker-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/hacker-culture/</guid>
      <description>Hacker and doubt Over time I matched the hacker culture with the culture of doubt.
So contributing to the hacker culture would mean contributing to the culture of doubt. But I guess this doesn’t mean a lot.
In this regard, I would start from the relationship between hackers and doubt.
Who is a hacker? A definition of hacker that goes straight to the point is:
A hacker is nothing but a person who loves to understand how things work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUCTF 2020 Writeup - Pick Up That CAN</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/pick-up-that-can-auctf2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/pick-up-that-can-auctf2020/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the only challenge I solved in the Signals section.
It’s been solved 59 times and it was worth 965 points.
Description:
Here’s a log of some kind of network traffic. The BASH script will help you set up your tools, and probably give you a hint as to what kind of network this is.
You can download the log here.
$ sha256sum pickupthatcan.log 6cd893bf99bf233d452aaa56ed65fcca51fef4e97493efa3ba6a44a0af03e95a pickupthatcan.log The shell script is really short.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUCTF 2020 Writeup - Password Cracking Challenges</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/password-cracking-challenges-auctf2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/password-cracking-challenges-auctf2020/</guid>
      <description>Salty This challenge was solved 148 times and it was worth 357 points.
Description:
You might need this: 1337
Hash: 5eaff45e09bec5222a9cfa9502a4740d
NOTE: The flag is NOT in the standard auctf{} format
The hash seems a salted MD5.
The correct hash mode is md5($salt.$pass). So with hashcat:
$ hashcat -a 0 -m 20 salty rockyou.txt ..... 5eaff45e09bec5222a9cfa9502a4740d:1337:treetop ..... Crack Me 2 This challenge was solved 108 times and it was worth 880 points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUCTF 2020 Writeup - Remote School</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/remote-school-auctf2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/remote-school-auctf2020/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the fourth and last pwn challenge. It was solved 63 times and it was worth 960 points.
Description:
Dear Student,
Due to COVID-19 concerns our curriculum will be moving completely to online courses… I know we haven’t even started our school year yet so this may come as a shock. But I promise it won’t be too bad! You can login at challenges.auctf.com 30013.
Best, Dean of Eon Pillars</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUCTF 2020 Writeup - House of Madness</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/house-of-madness-auctf2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/house-of-madness-auctf2020/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the third pwn challenge. It was solved 100 times and it was worth 897 points.
Description:
Welcome to the House of Madness. Can you pwn your way to the keys to get the relic?
nc challenges.auctf.com 30012
Note: ASLR is disabled for this challenge
You could download the binary here.
$ sha256sum ./house_of_madness 15b1a68ae0e1d4eee4f917cc92412d90fd3a4adbb5a55a83b115e0f438baaf93 house_of_madness Exploitation When we launch the program shows a banner and it asks us to make a choice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AUCTF 2020 Writeup - Thanksgiving Dinner</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/thanksgiving-dinner-auctf2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/thanksgiving-dinner-auctf2020/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the second pwn challenge of AUCTF 2020. It was solved 238 times and it was worth 408 points.
Description:
I just ate a huge dinner. I can barley eat anymore… so please don’t give me too much!
nc challenges.auctf.com 30011
Note: ASLR is disabled for this challenge
You could download the binary here
$ sha256sum ./thanksgiving_dinner 2307af59beead6a2377c3beb2ff26f70d5732ec6b651b5c31e58b8f692bfb70c thanksgiving_dinner Exploitation The program simply ask for an input. But it seems not vulnerable to a buffer overflow:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shellcode Injection - Old but gold</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/mprotect-urop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/mprotect-urop/</guid>
      <description>Intro Some time ago, a friend of mine (dag-tech), asked me about a technique to run a shellcode with NX enabled. So he gave me a simple program:
//src.c #include &amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt; #include &amp;lt;unistd.h&amp;gt; int main(int argc, char **argv) { char buf[16]; puts(&amp;#34;Can you pwn me????&amp;#34;); read(0, buf, 512); return 0; } $ gcc -z noexecstack -fno-stack-protector -o vuln src.c $ checksec vuln Arch: amd64-64-little RELRO: Partial RELRO Stack: No canary found NX: NX enabled PIE: No PIE (0x400000) The approach The issue with NX is that we cannot execute code in writable memory segment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackCon&#39;19 writeup - baby b0f</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/babyb0f-hackcon19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/babyb0f-hackcon19/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the first and easiest pwn challenge. It was solved 117 times and it’s worth 100 points.
Description:
It’s a b0f , Can’t be easier than that.
You could download the binary here.
$ sha256sum ./babyb0f 68344bb2c6aa56fdcc75379b3ced882abdf4e9bffa0bba63006dfb6c11ed7c47 babyb0f Exploitation The program simply asks for an input that overflow a buffer:
$ ./baby_b0f AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA Try Again Segmentation fault (core dumped) $ checksec ./baby_b0f Arch: amd64-64-little RELRO: Partial RELRO Stack: No canary found NX: NX enabled PIE: No PIE (0x400000) As usual I opened the binary with r2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackCon&#39;19 writeup - babypwn</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/babypwn-hackcon19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/babypwn-hackcon19/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the second pwn challenge. It was solved 36 times and it’s worth 451 points.
Description:
You don’t need eip control for every pwn.
You can download the binary here
$ sha256sum ./babypwn 57b32556465e890bdefdcccd6e515f6a2888300f48e9b7a7df0bb66694bda45b babypwn Exploitation The program asks five input, echoes them back and prints a message of failure. However there is a segfault caused by a buffer overflow.
$ ./babypwn 1 2 3 4 5 1 2 3 4 5 Naaa , Try HArder $ .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackCon&#39;19 writeup - Not So Easy B0f</title>
      <link>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/notsoeasyb0f-hackcon19/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://raffaeleflorio.github.io/post/notsoeasyb0f-hackcon19/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is the third pwn challenge. It was solved 29 times and it’s worth 469 points.
Description:
I have stack canaries enabled, Can you still B0f me ?
In addition to the binary there is also a specific libc.
You can download the binary here and the libc here
$ sha256sum notsoeasyb0f notsoeasyb0f-libc.so 9cdc861043359904c6807d31990f7369c1fec2d25e545e263bb4ae2e5786883e notsoeasyb0f 74ca69ada4429ae5fce87f7e3addb56f1b53964599e8526244fecd164b3c4b44 notsoeasyb0f-libc.so Exploitation This program asks for a name, echoes it back, then it asks a sentence.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
